(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(테마 음악 재생)
FAMILY: THE UNBREAKABLE BOND
가족: 깨지지 않는 유대
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(침울한 음악 재생)
(KID COUGHS)
(아이 기침)
(COUGHS)
(기침)
(THUDS)
(쿵)
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
(GRUNTS)
(끙끙거림)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(극적인 음악 재생)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(브레이크 소음)
MAN: From now on,
남: 지금부터,
this will be your house.
이것이 당신의 집이 될 것입니다.
If you can survive here,
여기서 살아남을 수 있다면,
you won't have to starve.
굶지 않아도 됩니다.
But you will not have any freedom.
그러나 당신에게는 자유가 없을 것입니다.
You either take it or leave it.
가져가거나 버리거나 둘 중 하나입니다.
Come out.
나오세요.
-(PUNCHES LANDING) -(BOY AND GIRL GRUNTING)
-(펀치 랜딩) -(소년과 소녀가 투덜거림)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(그렁거림이 계속됨)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(침울한 음악 재생)
(GRUNTS)
(끙끙거림)
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
(달리는 발자국)
(YELLS)
(소리친다)
(PANTING)
(헥헥)
(SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES)
(침울한 음악이 계속됩니다)
You must be Minseo.
당신이 민서이군요.
Minseo.
민서.
How long has it been?
얼마나 됐나요?
I was worried about you after we parted.
헤어지고 나서 걱정이 됐어요.
But...
하지만...
You look fine, that's disappointing.
괜찮아 보이는데, 실망스럽네요.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(엘리베이터 벨 소리)
Honey.
여보.
Who the heck are you?
도대체 당신은 누구입니까?
What the heck are you doing to my family?
도대체 뭐하는 거야? 내 가족에게?
Who are you?
누구세요?
Tell me.
말해 주세요.
Tell me, you prick.
말해봐, 이 새끼야.
-Let this go. -DOHOON: Why are you here?
-이거 놔둬. -도훈: 왜 여기 있어요?
Say it!
말해보세요!
Dohoon.
도훈.
Honey, what are you doing? Stop.
여보, 뭐 하는 거야? 멈추다.
-Say it! -Stop it.
-말해봐! -그만해요.
Cousin.
사촌.
(PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(장난스러운 음악 재생)
He's my cousin.
그 사람은 내 사촌이야.
He returned recently. (CHUCKLES)
그는 최근에 돌아왔습니다. (웃음)
DOHOON: Cousin?
도훈: 사촌?
(IN ENGLISH) Oh, cousin?
(영어로) 아, 사촌?
DOHOON: Hmm.
도훈: 흠.
-(IN KOREAN) Oh. My cousin-in-law. -(CHUCKLES)
-(한국어로) 아. 내 사촌. -(웃음)
Oh, he's my cousin-in-law. (LAUGHS)
아, 그 사람은 내 사촌이에요. (웃음)
This is crazy.
이건 미친 짓이야.
Cousin!
사촌!
You're my cousin-in-law. (LAUGHING)
당신은 내 사촌이에요. (웃음)
Long time no see.
오랜만이군요.
Wait, it's our first time.
잠깐만요, 우리 처음이에요.
Nice to meet you, Cousin.
만나서 반가워요, 사촌님.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
This feels weird.
느낌이 이상해요.
So you're my cousin-in-law. (LAUGHS)
그럼 당신은 내 사촌이군요. (웃음)
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
Oh, a cousin.
아, 사촌이군요.
My cousin-in-law. (LAUGHING)
내 사촌. (웃음)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYS)
(테마 음악 재생)
FAMILY: THE UNBREAKABLE BOND
가족: 깨지지 않는 유대
EPISODE 7
에피소드 7
DOHOON: I didn't know
도훈: 몰랐어요
Yura had a cousin.
유라에게는 사촌이 있었습니다.
How have I not seen you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 보지 못했습니까?
MAN: I was in Thailand.
MAN: 저는 태국에 있었어요.
DOHOON: Thailand?
도훈: 태국?
What were you doing in Thailand?
태국에서는 무엇을 하고 계셨나요?
MAN: I ran a business.
MAN: 저는 사업을 했어요.
DOHOON: What kind of business?
도훈: 어떤 사업이요?
MAN: I sold heaters.
MAN: 히터를 팔았어요.
DOHOON: You sold heaters in Thailand?
도훈: 태국에서 히터를 팔았나요?
That's new. (LAUGHING)
그것은 새로운 것입니다. (웃음)
So you were in Thailand, you should've told me.
그럼 태국에 계셨군요. 나한테 말했어야 했는데.
Huh? (LAUGHING)
뭐? (웃음)
That's a bummer.
정말 안타까운 일이네요.
We could've run the business together.
우리는 함께 사업을 운영할 수도 있었습니다.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(둘 다 웃음)
I go to Thailand sometimes for business trips.
태국에 가끔 가는데 출장용.
So you probably met her when she visited Thailand this time.
그럼 아마 그녀를 만났을 거예요 이번에 태국을 방문했을 때.
Oh, no.
안 돼.
Why didn't you tell me your cousin was in Thailand?
왜 나한테 말하지 않았어? 네 사촌이 태국에 있었어?
Uh... (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
어... (긴장해서 낄낄거림)
Minseo, get up.
민서야, 일어나라.
It's cold, come to Mommy.
추워요 엄마한테 와요
You should've called me.
나한테 전화했어야 했는데.
Ah... You should understand.
아... 이해하셔야 합니다.
Actually,
실제로,
we were supposed to go to Thailand for our wedding anniversary,
우리는 태국에 가기로 했어요 우리 결혼기념일을 맞아,
but she got all upset because of me.
그런데 그 사람이 나 때문에 완전 화를 냈어요.
So she went by herself.
그래서 그녀는 혼자 갔다.
She was probably too busy to contact you.
그녀는 아마 너무 바빴을 거예요 당신에게 연락하기 위해.
-Right, honey? -(BOTH CHUCKLE)
-그렇지, 얘야? -(둘 다 웃음)
You should sleep in your room.
네 방에서 자야 해.
Uncle, don't leave.
삼촌, 떠나지 마세요.
Let's play together again tomorrow.
내일 또 같이 놀자.
Minseo likes you so much.
민서가 당신을 너무 좋아해요.
Honey.
꿀.
For our next family trip, how does Thailand sound? Huh?
다음 가족여행으로는 태국은 어때요? 뭐?
(CHUCKLING HESITANTLY) Yeah, well...
(머뭇거리며) 응, 뭐...
You should clean up and go to bed. It's late.
청소를 하고 잠자리에 드셔야 합니다. 늦었어.
Goodnight.
안녕히 주무세요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
If we go to Thailand, do you have a place for us to stay?
태국에 가게 된다면, 우리가 묵을 곳이 있나요?
Of course.
물론.
Feel free to come.
부담 없이 오세요.
Really?
정말?
Such a generous guy.
정말 관대한 사람이에요.
Wow. (LAUGHS) Let's drink.
우와. (웃음) 마시자.
You're amazing, nice to meet you. (CHUCKLES)
정말 대단해요, 만나서 반가워요. (웃음)
(SLOW SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(느리고 침울한 음악 재생)
-Mom. -Yes?
-엄마. -예?
Is Tae a last name?
태가 성인가요?
He said his name is Taegu.
이름이 대구라고 하더군요.
It's new.
새로운 것입니다.
(YAWNS)
(하품)
Uncle must have missed you so much.
삼촌이 당신을 많이 그리워했나 봐요.
Mm, time for bed, close your eyes.
음, 잘 시간이야, 눈을 감아.
I want to play more with Uncle.
나는 삼촌과 더 놀고 싶다.
If you grew up with Yura,
유라와 함께 자랐다면,
you probably know all about her past.
당신은 아마도 그녀의 과거에 대해 모두 알고있을 것입니다.
That's amazing.
정말 놀랍습니다.
You should tell me about it
그것에 대해 나에게 말해야 해
from time to time, okay?
가끔씩, 알았지?
(LAUGHING)
(웃음)
You'll tell me, right?
나한테 말해줄 거지?
I feel relieved to see that she has settled down.
보고 있으면 마음이 편해진다 그녀가 자리를 잡았다는 것입니다.
She seems happy.
그녀는 행복해 보인다.
Really?
정말?
You don't look alike,
당신은 닮지 않은 것 같아요
but you are her family after all.
하지만 결국 당신은 그녀의 가족입니다.
There's something mysterious about you.
당신에게는 뭔가 신비로운 점이 있어요.
So I'm still struggling to get out
그래서 아직도 나가려고 애쓰고 있어요
of her charm.
그녀의 매력.
Why did you finally show up?
드디어 나타난 이유는 무엇인가요?
(LAUGHS)
(웃음)
Let's drink, nice to meet you, Cousin.
한잔하자, 만나서 반가워요, 사촌님.
-Cheers. -(GLASSES CLINK)
-건배. -(안경이 찰칵 소리가 난다)
Bottoms up. (CHUCKLES)
상향식. (웃음)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
(SPITS)
(침)
DOHOON: Ah!
도훈: 아!
(CHUCKLING) All right.
(낄낄거림) 알았어.
(SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES)
(침울한 음악이 계속됩니다)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
Leave before my husband wakes up.
남편이 일어나기 전에 떠나세요.
Get out of my house now.
지금 내 집에서 나가세요.
Who do you think you are to tell me what to do?
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까? 나한테 뭘 해야 할지 말하려고?
Have you forgotten who I was?
내가 누구인지 잊었나요?
I have no intention to put you in hell.
나는 당신을 지옥에 넣을 생각이 없습니다.
I'm just here to resolve things.
나는 단지 문제를 해결하기 위해 여기에 있을 뿐입니다.
You need to finish up Wolfe's job.
Wolfe의 일을 끝내야 해요.
-(CHUCKLES) -Once you settle it,
-(웃음) -일단 해결하고 나면
no harm will be done to you or your family.
해를 끼치 지 않을 것입니다 당신이나 당신의 가족에게.
You have a nice husband and a lovely girl.
당신에겐 좋은 남편이 있어요 그리고 사랑스러운 소녀.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(심호흡)
Won't you have to protect your family?
가족을 보호해야 하지 않겠습니까?
Get some sleep.
잠을 좀 자세요.
You must be tired.
피곤하겠네요.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(휴대전화 진동)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
So? How did it go?
그래서? 어떻게 됐나요?
MA: (ON PHONE) There was a transaction in Busan.
엄마: (전화로) 부산에서 거래가 있었습니다.
They took three Makarov pistols,
그들은 마카로프 권총 세 자루를 가져갔고
three Udav 6P72-1
3개의 Udav 6P72-1
and two SVDs.
그리고 두 개의 SVD.
I heard MGD only uses Russian guns
MGD는 러시아 총만 쓴다고 들었는데
because they're used to it.
왜냐하면 그들은 그것에 익숙하기 때문입니다.
That confirms it.
그것은 그것을 확인합니다.
Get the sketch of people who bought the weapons in Busan.
구매한 사람들의 스케치를 받아보세요 부산의 무기.
Secure the camera footages at the time
당시 카메라 영상을 확보하세요
and trace the direction they went.
그리고 그들이 가는 방향을 추적해 보세요.
Because of what happened to Bullet,
Bullet에게 일어난 일 때문에,
Warrior is on the move fast.
전사가 빠르게 움직이고 있습니다.
Then their next target will be
그렇다면 그들의 다음 목표는
Hwacha or Butterfly.
화차 또는 나비.
We must be ahead of them this time.
이번에는 우리가 그들보다 앞서야 합니다.
I'll send it to you as soon as it's ready.
내가 보내줄게 준비가 되자마자.
Hmm.
흠.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
YOON CHERRY
윤체리
(LINE RINGING)
(라인 벨 울림)
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(휴대전화 진동)
OH CHUNRYUN
오천륜
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(부드럽게 신음)
Hello? Do you know what time it is?
안녕하세요? 지금이 몇 시인지 아시나요?
You're back, why didn't you call?
돌아왔어, 왜 전화 안 했어?
What about Hwacha?
화차는 어때요?
Hello? Cherry?
안녕하세요? 벚나무?
(GROANS)
(신음소리)
I shouldn't have come.
난 오지 말았어야 했는데.
I forgot.
잊어버렸어요.
I forgot what you were like.
나는 당신이 어떤 사람인지 잊어버렸어요.
-Report. -Hmm...
-보고서. -흠...
Hwacha. Real name's Yoon Sanghoon.
화차. 본명은 윤상훈.
Born in 1944.
1944년생.
Age 79.
79세.
Lived in Kazan, Russia until 2013.
2013년까지 러시아 카잔에서 살았습니다.
Are you still sleeping?
아직도 자고 있나요?
You think I don't know the information?
내가 정보를 모른다고 생각하시나요?
Wake up.
깨우다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
For 12 years he lived in Kazan,
그는 12년 동안 카잔에 살았습니다.
he's made three phone calls, and they're all to the same number.
그 사람은 전화를 세 번이나 했고, 그리고 그들은 모두 같은 숫자입니다.
And that was from Korea?
그런데 그게 한국에서 온 건가요?
Where's that?
그게 어디야?
By the way, are you paying for my homecoming party today?
그런데, 당신은 지불하고 있습니까? 오늘 내 홈커밍 파티에?
(CHUCKLES) Are we going to that place?
(웃음) 우리 거기로 갈 거예요?
We always went there. What was the name?
우리는 항상 거기에 갔다. 이름이 뭐였나요?
They had the best beer on tap. (CHUCKLES)
그들은 최고의 맥주를 마실 수 있었습니다. (웃음)
(CHIEF OH SIGHS)
(오 과장님 한숨)
Wonju.
원주.
Hwacha's in Wonju.
화차는 원주에 있어요.
The call from Goyeon-dong, Wonju three years ago
원주 고연동에서 온 전화 3년 전
was the first and the last.
처음이자 마지막이었다.
Good. Well done.
좋은. 잘하셨어요.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(휴대전화 진동)
Did everyone else arrive?
다른 사람들은 다 왔나요?
No, I have something on my mind for Butterfly.
아니요, 생각나는 게 있어요 나비를 위해.
Just stick to the plan.
그냥 계획대로 하세요.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
Oh? Cousin?
아? 사촌?
Cousin?
사촌?
-Yes. -Hello!
-예. -안녕하세요!
Welcome!
환영!
-(CRACKER POPPING) -(WHOOPS)
-(크래커 터지는 소리) -(으악)
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
-Here. -Welcome.
-여기. -환영.
Welcome.
환영.
(WHOOPS)
(으악)
I'm glad you're here.
당신이 여기 있어서 기뻐요.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
DOHOON: What's all the noise?
도훈: 무슨 소리가 다 들려?
Dad.
아빠.
Cousin.
사촌.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
-Let's go in. -Dohoon.
-들어가자. -도훈.
Welcome.
환영.
We're here.
우리는 여기에 있습니다.
Stay seated, it's okay.
앉으세요. 괜찮아요.
Have a seat here.
여기 앉으세요.
No need to move, sit down.
움직일 필요 없이 앉으세요.
JIHOON: Dohoon, help. MIRIM: Dohoon, can you give us a hand?
지훈: 도훈아, 도와줘. 미림: 도훈아, 우리 좀 도와줄래?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(소프트 음악 재생)
WOONGSOO: Sit down here.
웅수: 여기 앉으세요.
-Sit here. -Come on.
- 여기 앉으세요. -어서 해봐요.
Come closer.
가까이 오세요.
WOONGSOO: Here.
웅수: 여기요.
Ahh...
아아...
I'm good.
난 괜찮아.
Things were a bit hectic,
일이 좀 바빴고,
I should've prepared it in advance.
미리 준비해두었어야 했는데.
I'm sorry, Father.
죄송해요, 아버지.
It's okay, try it. Don't be shy.
괜찮아요, 시도해 보세요. 부끄러워하지 마세요.
I woke up early to make this for you.
나는 당신을 위해 이것을 만들기 위해 일찍 일어났습니다.
Here.
여기.
How is it?
어때요?
We've met, right?
우리 만난 적 있죠?
MINSEO: Uncle, do you like spicy rice cakes?
민서: 삼촌, 너는 매운 떡을 좋아하니?
Should I buy them for you?
내가 당신을 위해 그것들을 사야 할까요?
Minseo.
민서.
Did you pack your homework? Let's go check your bag one more time.
숙제는 챙겼나요? 가방을 한 번 더 확인하러 가자.
-Let's go. -Wait.
-갑시다. -기다리다.
Did you know Dongdaemun Stadium is gone now?
알고 계셨나요? 동대문운동장은 이제 없어졌나요?
Are you sad? (CHUCKLES)
슬프나요? (웃음)
YURA: Minseo. JIHOON: Cousin.
유라: 민서. 지훈: 사촌.
Make yourself at home.
집처럼 편안하게 지내세요.
Take your jacket off. Open your arms.
재킷을 벗으세요. 팔을 벌리세요.
-Wow, you're in shape. -YURA: Minseo, come here.
-와, 몸매가 좋으시군요. -YURA: 민서야, 이리 와봐.
Why are you taking his jacket off?
왜 그 사람 재킷을 벗는 거야?
Minseo.
민서.
DOHOON: Cousin, don't you want to go?
도훈: 사촌형, 가고 싶지 않아?
There's Mount Namsan nearby.
근처에 남산이 있어요.
They have cable cars
케이블카가 있어요
and real nice pork cutlets there, right?
그리고 거기 진짜 맛있는 돈까스도 있고, 맞죠?
-Aren't you going to work? -Right.
- 회사 안 가시나요? -오른쪽.
On that cable car, you get a nice bird's-eye view of Seoul,
그 케이블카에서는 서울의 멋진 조감도를 볼 수 있고,
-it's magnificent. You'd love it. -(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
-멋지네요. 당신은 그것을 좋아할 것입니다. -(휴대폰이 진동함)
-Hurry, go. -I got a call.
-어서 가세요. -전화가 왔습니다.
YOON CHERRY
윤체리
Cousin, think about where you want to go.
사촌아, 생각해봐 당신이 가고 싶은 곳.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
(SQUEALS) Oh!
(비명을 지르며) 오!
Why are you playing dumb?
왜 멍청한 짓을 하는 거야?
You know me.
당신은 나를 알고 있습니다.
(HESITANTLY) I'm not sure.
(머뭇거리며) 잘 모르겠어요.
Cousin, is this real?
삼촌, 이게 진짜예요?
Can I try it on?
입어봐도 될까요?
This is legit.
이것은 합법적입니다.
So, did you find what I asked?
그럼 내가 물어본 걸 찾았나요?
(IN ENGLISH) MGD.
(영어로) MGD.
-(IN KOREAN) What's that? -CHERRY: Yes.
-(한국어로) 그게 뭔데? -체리: 네.
That tattoo on your friend.
네 친구의 문신 말이야.
It's some kind of tradition they have.
그것은 그들이 가지고 있는 일종의 전통입니다.
But the tattoos looked a bit different
근데 문신이 좀 달라보였어
on Carly Young and Wolfe. Why is that?
칼리 영(Carly Young)과 울프(Wolfe)에 대해. 왜 그럴까요?
Oh, MGD is actually a secret organization formed in the '70s
아, MGD는 사실 70년대에 결성된 비밀조직
and was named "Union" by the government.
정부에서는 "Union"으로 명명했습니다.
The government formed a secret organization?
정부가 결성됨 비밀조직?
A private one?
개인?
Interesting.
흥미로운.
So what happened?
그래서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
It gets a little expensive from here.
여기서부터 조금 비싸집니다.
Hey. I paid you last time.
여기요. 지난번에 돈을 냈어요.
Fine. Put it on a tab.
괜찮은. 탭에 올려 놓으세요.
So what happened?
그래서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
What happened next?
다음에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
At the time, there were a lot of spies around the world.
그 당시에는 스파이가 많았어요. 전세계.
Korea also formed a group of mercenaries to settle the affairs,
한국도 용병단을 결성했다 사건을 해결하기 위해,
but it was foundered in the late '90s.
하지만 90년대 후반에 설립되었습니다.
That's when the tattoo shape changed.
그때 문신 모양이 바뀌었어요.
That's the difference
그게 차이점이에요
between the Old Union and the New Union.
구연합과 신연합 사이.
The Old Union is made up of old members carrying out covert activities,
구연합(Old Union)은 옛 회원들로 구성되어 있다. 은밀한 활동을 펼치고,
it's more like a private group of killers.
그것은 더 비슷하다 개인 살인자 그룹.
New Union has a different intent.
New Union은 다른 의도를 가지고 있습니다.
They have been trafficking
그들은 인신매매를 해왔다
weapons, drugs and humans.
무기, 마약, 그리고 인간.
Should I say, they're more like a business group?
굳이 말하자면, 그들은 비즈니스 그룹에 더 가깝나요?
But it was Wolfe who killed Carly Young.
하지만 칼리 영을 죽인 사람은 울프였습니다.
Does that have something to do with the breakup of the organization?
그게 무슨 상관이 있는 걸까 조직이 해체되면서?
It looks like it.
그럴 것 같습니다.
New Union is trying to get rid of the remaining members of the Old,
뉴유니온은 이를 없애려고 노력하고 있다. 올드의 나머지 멤버들,
that's why they sent your friend.
그래서 그 사람들이 네 친구를 보낸 거야.
Then who's the sniper that killed Wolfe?
그렇다면 울프를 죽인 저격수는 누구일까요?
I'm not completely sure,
나는 완전히 확신하지 못한다.
-but I think... -Dad, Boseok is here.
-근데 내 생각엔... -아빠, 보석이 왔어요.
Dad, we need to go.
아빠, 우리 가봐야 해요.
Okay, let's go.
좋아, 가자.
I'll call you later.
나중에 전화할게요.
-Honey, you're late. -What?
-여보, 늦었어요. -무엇?
Right, we should go.
그래, 우리는 가야 해.
Bottoms up.
상향식.
-I'm good... -Drink.
- 난 괜찮아... -마셔요.
Okay.
좋아요.
That's what you live for.
그것이 당신이 사는 이유입니다.
Nice to meet you,
만나서 반가워요
I'm really glad.
정말 기쁘네요.
If you're Yura's family, we're all family.
유라의 가족이라면, 우리는 모두 가족이에요.
I'm glad you came.
당신이 와줘서 기뻐요.
Therefore I suggest a "love shot".
그래서 나는 '러브샷'을 제안한다.
A "love shot"?
'러브샷'?
Love shot, love shot.
러브샷, 러브샷.
JIHOON: Hold on.
지훈: 잠깐만요.
Cousin, let me know where you wanna go.
사촌님, 어디로 가고 싶은지 알려주세요.
We can go this weekend, okay?
이번 주말에 갈 수 있겠네요, 그렇죠?
Dad, treat him nicely.
아빠, 그 사람을 잘 대해주세요.
Hey, you too, be nice.
야, 너도 잘 지내라.
Right.
오른쪽.
Minseo, say bye.
민서야, 안녕.
Have a good day.
좋은 하루 보내세요.
Uncle, see you later.
삼촌, 나중에 봐요.
DOHOON: See you later. Let's go.
도훈: 이따 봐요. 갑시다.
No, sit down.
아니, 앉으세요.
Have a bite.
한 입 먹어보세요.
I heard you had a hard time in Thailand.
태국에서 힘든 시간을 보냈다고 들었습니다.
-Yes. -Is it easy to get a job there?
-예. - 거기 취업하기 쉽나요?
If I go there,
내가 거기 가면,
do I get to wear a 30 million won watch like you?
내가 입을 수 있을까? 너처럼 3천만원짜리 시계?
Wearing a watch like this,
이렇게 시계를 차고,
you must be a capable man.
당신은 유능한 사람이어야합니다.
Ewha Womans University, Class of '16. Fashion design major.
이화여자대학교, 16학년. 패션디자인 전공.
Kim Jiyoung.
김지영.
You used to date her.
당신은 그녀와 데이트하곤 했어요.
You threw her a surprise event at our school.
당신은 그녀에게 깜짝 이벤트를 던졌습니다 우리 학교에서.
She was my colleague.
그녀는 내 동료였습니다.
-Have one more. -Yes.
-하나 더 드세요. -예.
MIRIM: Oh.
미림: 아.
Don't play dumb!
바보 같은 짓은 하지 마세요!
One second. My goodness.
1초. 이럴 수가.
-(CELL PHONE BEEPS) -(LINE RINGING)
-(휴대폰 신호음) -(라인 벨 울림)
Jiyoung!
지영!
(ON PHONE) Mirim, what's up?
(전화로) 미림 씨, 무슨 일이에요?
-Guess who I'm with. -Who?
-내가 누구랑 같이 있는지 맞춰보세요. -WHO?
Don't be surprised.
놀라지 마세요.
Ta-da.
짜잔.
Do you recognize him?
당신은 그를 알아요?
The guy you dated in university.
당신이 대학에서 데이트했던 남자.
Hey! What's that jerk doing in your house?
여기요! 저 새끼 뭐하는 거야? 당신 집에?
-(COUGHING) -You scumbag!
-(기침) -이 쓰레기야!
I'll root up your eyes!
네 눈을 뽑아주겠어!
You bastard!
이 개자식!
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Cousin, get up. One, two, three.
사촌, 일어나세요. 하나 둘 셋.
-One, two. -(GRUNTING)
- 하나, 둘. -(끙끙거리는 소리)
JIHOON: One, two.
지훈: 하나, 둘.
One, two.
하나, 둘.
You can do it. One, two.
할 수 있어요. 하나, 둘.
(GRUNTS, COUGHS)
(끙, 기침)
JIHOON: Are you okay?
지훈: 괜찮아요?
One more time?
한 번 더요?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
(JIHOON SIGHS)
(지훈이 한숨)
I guess you could barely eat in Thailand.
거의 못먹을 것 같은데 태국에서.
I know it's good, but you still need to chew.
나는 그것이 좋은 것을 안다. 하지만 여전히 씹어야 해요.
-Are you okay? -I'm okay now.
-괜찮으세요? -이제 괜찮아요.
(PANTING)
(헥헥)
WOONGSOO: Sit down.
웅수: 앉으세요.
We should feed him well, Yura.
잘 먹여야지, 유라.
Yes.
예.
Your cousin almost died.
당신의 사촌은 거의 죽을 뻔했습니다.
Yura, I saved him.
유라, 내가 구했어.
Oh.
오.
(SIGHS SOFTLY)
(부드럽게 한숨을 쉬다)
Just play along and leave soon.
그냥 같이 놀고 빨리 떠나세요.
You haven't given me an answer yet.
당신은 아직 나에게 대답을 주지 않았습니다.
You think I'm staying put because I can't handle you?
넌 내가 가만히 있을 거라고 생각하지? 내가 널 감당할 수 없으니까?
I dare you.
감히.
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(침울한 음악 재생)
Huh?
응?
You want to stab me, but you don't dare, do you?
나를 찌르고 싶어하는구나, 하지만 감히 그럴 수가 없지, 그렇지?
See?
보다?
You haven't changed.
당신은 변하지 않았습니다.
You can't do anything.
당신은 아무것도 할 수 없습니다.
What's the point
요점이 무엇입니까?
of wearing an expensive suit and a 30 million won watch?
값비싼 양복을 입는 것 그리고 3천만원짜리 시계?
You couldn't even make it to your cousin's wedding.
넌 해내지도 못했지 사촌 결혼식에.
You didn't even know you had a niece.
당신은 조카가 있다는 사실조차 몰랐습니다.
No matter how busy you are, you shouldn't be like that.
아무리 바빠도 당신은 그렇게해서는 안됩니다.
We have someone just like you in the family. Over there.
우리에겐 당신 같은 사람이 있어요 가족에서. 저기요.
Which one makes you happier, seeing more zeros in your account,
어느 쪽이 당신을 더 행복하게 만드는지, 귀하의 계정에 0이 더 많이 표시되는 경우
or feeding your child something good?
아니면 아이에게 좋은 것을 먹이나요?
That depends on how many zeros it is.
이는 0이 몇 개인지에 따라 다릅니다.
Hey!
여기요!
(ECHOING) You should live the rest of your life right.
(반향) 나머지는 네가 살아야 해 네 인생 말이야.
Having no money isn't what makes you poor.
돈이 없는 것은 아니다 무엇이 당신을 가난하게 만드는가?
Being money-blinded and having no one around
돈에 눈이 멀다 그리고 주변에 아무도 없어서
is what makes you poor.
그것이 당신을 가난하게 만드는 것입니다.
Keep that in mind, okay?
명심하세요, 알았죠?
(ECHOING)
(반향)
(ECHOING STOPS) Okay?
(메아리가 멈춤) 알았지?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(초인종이 울림)
-(INTERCOM BEEPS) -WOMAN: Mr. Kwon.
-(인터콤 신호음) -여자: 권 씨.
I'm here to help you with kimchi.
나는 김치 만드는 것을 도와주러 왔습니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
-Hello. -WOONGSOO: I'm glad you're here.
-안녕하세요. -웅수: 와줘서 기뻐요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Hello, Mr. Kwon.
안녕하세요, 권 선생님.
Jihoon, how are you?
지훈아, 잘 지내?
Good.
좋은.
What brings you here?
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
I missed his 80th birthday party.
나는 그의 80번째 생일 파티를 놓쳤다.
I can't miss this. (CHUCKLES)
나는 이것을 놓칠 수 없다. (웃음)
No pressure.
압력이 없습니다.
I'm only here to help you.
나는 단지 당신을 돕기 위해 여기에 있습니다.
You all look familiar,
다들 낯익어 보이시는데,
but who's he?
그런데 그 사람은 누구죠?
WOONGSOO: He's our family too.
웅수: 그 사람도 우리 가족이에요.
He's Yura's cousin.
그는 유라의 사촌이에요.
Ah-ha. Hmm.
아하. 흠.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
I'm Park Bunsoon.
저는 박분순이에요.
Hi.
안녕.
So, how much have you done?
그럼, 얼마나 했나요?
We just started.
우리는 방금 시작했습니다.
I'm here right on time. (LAUGHS)
나는 정시에 여기에 왔습니다. (웃음)
Now,
지금,
shall we start?
시작해볼까?
Is your cousin
당신의 사촌인가요?
joining us?
우리와 합류?
He's from Thailand, he has no idea.
그 사람은 태국 출신인데 전혀 모르는 사람이에요.
Oh, my.
아, 이런.
All the more reason for him to join us then, Mr. Kwon.
그에게 더 많은 이유가 있습니다 그럼 같이 갑시다, 권 선생님.
-What? -We must work together to get closer.
-무엇? -더 가까워지려면 함께 노력해야 해요.
WOONGSOO: Right,
웅수: 그렇죠,
-come here. -Join us.
-이리로 오세요. - 우리와 함께하세요.
-But... -MS. PARK: Gosh, you're heavy.
-하지만... -MS. PARK: 맙소사, 너 무거워.
Join us.
우리와 함께하세요.
-JIHOON: Cousin, do you need gloves? -No, I'm good.
-지훈: 사촌형 장갑 필요해요? -아니요, 저는 괜찮아요.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(경쾌한 음악 재생)
Gosh, my legs.
맙소사, 내 다리.
Cousin,
사촌,
did you think making kimchi was some kind of children's play?
김치를 담그는 것이 일종의 어린이 놀이?
Wouldn't it be more convenient
좀 더 편리하지 않을까
to just rub it in here?
그냥 여기에 문질러볼까?
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
Are you making a mush?
머쉬를 만들고 있나요?
The essence is all about the texture. (CLICKS TONGUE)
본질은 질감에 관한 것입니다. (혀를 클릭함)
Come on.
어서.
I'll need to use the restroom.
화장실을 이용해야겠어요.
-WOONGSOO: Okay, hurry. -Yes.
-웅수: 알았어, 서둘러. -예.
-The restroom is over there. -Thanks.
-화장실은 저기 있어요. -감사해요.
What is this? (SNIFFS)
이게 뭔가요? (훌쩍)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(무뚝뚝한 잡담)
Here you go.
여기요.
Oh, thank you.
아, 고마워요.
(GRUNTS)
(끙끙거림)
How much is it?
얼마인가요?
I'll give you the money
돈은 내가 줄게
the gold digger took from you.
금 파는 사람이 당신에게서 가져갔습니다.
I'll pay you instead.
내가 대신 지불할게요.
So let's not kill him.
그러니 그를 죽이지 말자.
(SIGHS) I mean,
(한숨) 내 말은,
I had fun too.
나도 재미있었습니다.
So I was going to let it slide.
그래서 나는 그것을 미끄러지도록 놔두려고했습니다.
But that jerk was just so shameless.
그런데 그 멍청이는 너무 뻔뻔했어요.
Look at you, you idiot.
좀 봐, 바보야.
You idiot!
바보야!
You are just unbelievable.
당신은 정말 믿을 수 없습니다.
My legs are fine.
내 다리는 괜찮아요.
Your hospital cost.
병원비.
The company's going to reimburse it. Just so you know.
회사에서 보상해 드릴 예정입니다. 그냥 알아두세요.
You should take this chance to quit smoking.
이 기회를 잡아야 해 담배를 끊으려고.
Your bones will get old and brittle!
뼈가 늙어 부서지기 쉬울 것입니다!
These are good for your bones.
이것은 뼈에 좋습니다.
I heard it's very good.
아주 좋다고 들었습니다.
JAEYEOL: Oh, this is sweet.
재열: 아, 맛있네요.
How nice of you.
정말 친절해요.
You always come empty-handed,
늘 빈손으로 오시는데,
and finally on the day I'm out...
그리고 드디어 나가는 날...
That's real good.
정말 좋아요.
JAEYEOL: Huh?
재열: 응?
You don't even know how to open it.
당신은 그것을 여는 방법조차 모릅니다.
Open it from the side, you prick.
옆에서 열어봐, 이 멍청아.
(GRUNTS)
(끙끙거림)
DOHOON: Yes, drink up.
도훈: 네, 마셔요.
He's drinking it alone.
그 사람 혼자 마시고 있어요.
(SIGHS) By the way,
(한숨) 그런데,
didn't you separate because you didn't want to see each other?
너 때문에 헤어진 거 아니었어? 서로 보고 싶지 않았어?
If you're going meet this often, just get back together.
자주 만날 예정이라면 그냥 다시 모이세요.
Good job, buddy. Keep going.
잘했어요, 친구. 계속하세요.
What are you, a magnet?
당신은 자석입니까?
She's dragging you around.
그녀는 당신을 끌고 있습니다.
Don't let her drag you around.
그녀가 당신을 끌고 다니도록 놔두지 마세요.
You too. Stop taking advantage of him.
너도. 그를 이용하지 마세요.
JAEYEOL: What's the problem?
재열: 뭐가 문제야?
I like being dragged around,
끌려다니는 걸 좋아하는데,
she likes taking advantages,
그녀는 이득을 취하는 걸 좋아해요
it's a perfect match.
그것은 완벽한 일치입니다.
Ah.
아.
Right.
오른쪽.
Enjoy your time, bye.
즐거운 시간 보내세요, 안녕.
-(SIGHS) -(DOOR CLOSES)
-(한숨) -(문이 닫힘)
Where are you going?
어디로 가시나요?
Aren't you seeing a doctor?
의사를 만나지 않습니까?
If you're not killing him,
그 사람을 죽이지 않는다면,
then we're done.
그러면 우리는 끝났습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
I have no use.
나는 쓸모가 없습니다.
I have to let you go.
나는 당신을 보내야합니다.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
Codename Bullet.
코드네임 Bullet.
The strongest suspect for the murder of Wolfe.
가장 유력한 용의자 울프 살해 혐의로.
Right.
오른쪽.
Shooting the Adam's apple is his style.
아담의 사과를 쏘는 것이 그의 스타일입니다.
Bullet?
총알?
Yes. If you look at Interpol's data,
예. 인터폴 자료를 보면
he received the highest honor for being a hero in the Vietnam War.
그는 최고의 영예를 얻었다 베트남 전쟁의 영웅이 되었기 때문입니다.
He became the leader of Union with Warrior
그는 연합의 지도자가 되었다 워리어와 함께
for his performance.
그의 공연을 위해.
Where are they all now?
지금 그 사람들은 모두 어디에 있나요?
I know Carly Young and Mole are dead.
나는 Carly Young과 Mole이 죽었다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
(INHALES SHARPLY) It's not 100 percent accurate,
(가쁜 숨을 들이쉰다) 100% 정확하지는 않지만,
but only four survived. Look.
하지만 4명만이 살아남았습니다. 바라보다.
The leader of MGD, Warrior,
MGD의 리더 워리어,
the sniper who shot Wolfe, Bullet,
울프를 쏜 저격수, 불릿,
Hwacha and Butterfly.
화차와 나비.
By the way, how are things between you and Chief?
그런데 상황은 어때요? 당신과 국장님 사이에요?
Oh Chunryun?
아 춘륜?
Nothing new.
새로운 것은 없습니다.
Why?
왜?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
MA: (OVER CALL) Confirming they have entered Gangwon Province.
MA: (통화 중) 그들이 가지고 있는지 확인 강원도에 입성했습니다.
They abandoned the car at the rest stop and moved separately.
휴게소에 차를 버렸어요 그리고 따로 옮겼다.
We're currently tracking their locations.
현재 추적 중입니다. 그들의 위치.
They're probably in Wonju.
아마 원주에 있을 거예요.
Search the area first.
먼저 해당 지역을 검색해 보세요.
Anything on Butterfly?
나비에 관한 건 없나요?
All clear.
공습 경보 신호.
If Butterfly moves within our boundary,
나비가 우리 경계 안에서 움직이면,
no matter what the Union does,
연합이 무엇을 하든 상관없다.
we're on standby to get them.
우리는 그것을 얻기 위해 대기 중입니다.
Secure maximum backup in Gangwon.
강원 최대의 백업을 확보하세요.
One more thing.
한 가지 더.
Switch to Plan B for Butterfly.
Butterfly에 대해서는 플랜 B로 전환하세요.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
Yura.
유라.
When are we having boiled pork?
돼지고기 삶은 언제 먹나요?
Oh, no.
안 돼.
I didn't buy any pork for the dish.
나는 요리에 사용할 돼지고기를 사지 않았습니다.
(GROANS)
(신음소리)
That was the most important part.
그것이 가장 중요한 부분이었습니다.
Can you go buy some with Jihoon?
지훈이랑 같이 좀 사갈래?
Please? (CHUCKLES)
제발? (웃음)
Okay.
알았어.
-Jihoon. -JIHOON: Yes?
-지훈. -지훈: 응?
Let's go buy meat.
고기 사러 가자
Okay. Should I get pork belly?
좋아요. 삼겹살을 먹어야 하나?
As always?
언제나처럼?
-I'll give you my card. -JIHOON: Okay.
- 내 카드를 줄게. -지훈: 그렇죠.
Jihoon, let's get fish breads on the way.
지훈아 생선빵 사먹자 가는 길에.
Sure.
확신하는.
MS. PARK: Isn't pork belly a bit too heavy?
MS. 박: 삼겹살 아닌가요? 좀 너무 무거워?
The hind leg is more reasonable
뒷다리가 더 합리적입니다
in terms of the price too, Mr. Kwon.
가격적인 면에서도 그렇죠, 권 선생님.
She's right, get the hind leg.
그녀 말이 맞아요. 뒷다리를 잡으세요.
Honey, you can stay with Bboongbboong.
여보, 붕붕이랑 같이 있으면 돼요.
Cousin.
사촌.
Let's go buy some meat.
고기 사러 가자.
Why?
왜?
I want fish bread.
나는 생선빵을 원해요.
I'll get them for you.
내가 가져다 드릴게요.
Cousin.
사촌.
Cousin?
사촌?
Let's go.
갑시다.
You can stop now, we have enough.
이제 그만해도 됩니다. 이제 충분합니다.
Take the gloves off.
장갑을 벗으세요.
You must be tired, you can stop now.
피곤하시겠군요. 이제 그만하셔도 됩니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
-Where are you two going? -What?
- 둘이 어디 가나요? -무엇?
Oh, right. We'll be right back.
아, 그렇죠. 곧 돌아오겠습니다.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
You should go with Mirim.
미림이랑 같이 가야 돼.
She had a tight stomach this morning. She should rest.
그녀는 오늘 아침에 배가 뻐근했어요. 그녀는 쉬어야 한다.
-Let's go, cousin. -I'll go with you.
- 가자, 사촌. - 나도 같이 갈게.
Let me just get changed, wait here.
옷 갈아입고 여기서 기다려요
No, I'll just go with you.
아니요, 그냥 같이 갈게요.
(MS. PARK SCREAMING)
(MS. 박 비명)
Why? Did you cut yourself?
왜요? 스스로 베셨나요?
Yura, come here.
유라야, 이리와봐
Oh, my gosh.
아, 이런.
I had a bad dream last night and worried something would happen,
어젯밤에 나쁜 꿈을 꿨어요 그리고 혹시 무슨 일이 일어날까봐 걱정했는데,
see, I end up bleeding.
보세요, 결국 피가 나네요.
Where's the first-aid kit?
구급상자는 어디에 있나요?
Jihoon!
지훈!
Oh, gosh.
아, 이런.
MAN: It's for boiled pork?
MAN: 삶은 돼지고기용인가요?
Between pork belly and hind leg, what would you like?
삼겹살과 뒷다리 사이, 무엇을 원하세요?
Which part do you want?
어떤 부분을 원하시나요?
You should decide.
당신은 결정해야합니다.
Pork belly or leg. What's it gonna be?
삼겹살이나 다리. 어떻게 될까요?
Just anything.
뭐든지.
I'll take pork belly.
저는 삼겹살을 가져갈게요.
Okay, pork belly it is.
좋아요, 삼겹살이에요.
JIHOON: Wait.
지훈: 잠깐만요.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(깊은 한숨)
The hind leg.
뒷다리.
The hind leg, okay.
뒷다리, 알았어.
-The hind leg-- -No, I want pork belly.
-뒷다리-- -아니요, 삼겹살을 원해요.
No, the hind leg.
아니, 뒷다리.
No, pork belly.
아니, 삼겹살.
Hind... No, belly... Hind, belly...
뒷다리... 아니, 배... 뒷다리, 배...
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
Cousin...
사촌...
I can't choose.
나는 선택할 수 없습니다.
You choose.
당신이 선택합니다.
-The hind-- -Mom always
-후다-- - 엄마는 항상
used pork belly for boiled pork because the hind leg is too tough.
삶은 돼지고기에는 삼겹살을 사용했어요 뒷다리가 너무 단단하기 때문이죠.
Who does she think she is to butt in and talk about what's reasonable?
그녀는 누구에게 맞붙을 것이라고 생각합니까? 무엇이 합리적인지 이야기해 보세요.
Am I not right?
내가 옳지 않은가?
All right, I'll give you both for half the price.
알았어, 둘 다 줄게 절반 가격으로.
Take both.
둘 다 가져 가라.
Happy now? Huh?
이제 행복해? 뭐?
Half and half?
반반?
For half the price?
절반 가격에?
No.
아니요.
We'll only take pork belly.
저희는 삼겹살만 먹겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Cousin.
사촌.
Cousin!
사촌!
Yes.
예.
After you.
당신 이후.
Wait.
기다리다.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(휴대전화 진동)
Yes, we're here.
네, 여기 있어요.
What?
무엇?
Really?
정말?
Okay, I'll be there in a minute.
알겠습니다. 곧 도착하겠습니다.
You should go in first.
당신이 먼저 들어가야 해요.
I'll explain it to you later.
나중에 설명하겠습니다.
The password is O five O eight asterisk.
비밀번호는 O5O8 별표입니다.
I'll take the fish bread.
생선빵을 가져갈게요.
Let yourself in.
스스로 들어가십시오.
One fish bread would've been nice.
생선빵 하나면 좋았을 텐데.
(LOCK KEYPAD BEEPING)
(잠금 키패드 소리)
(LOCK CHIMES)
(잠금 차임)
I got pork belly.
삼겹살이 나왔어요.
I brought pork belly.
삼겹살을 가져왔습니다.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(소프트 음악 재생)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
(MUMBLES INDISTINCTLY)
(무명하게 중얼거린다)
Careful.
조심하세요.
(MS. PARK GROANS)
(MS. 박 신음소리)
It's really okay, Ms. Park.
정말 괜찮아요, 박 선생님.
I can finish it up
마무리할 수 있어요
so don't worry and get some rest with Father.
그러니 걱정하지 말고 아버지랑 좀 쉬세요.
No.
아니요.
I should still finish it up.
아직 마무리해야 해요.
I even brought my secret sauce.
비법 소스도 가져왔어요.
I never leave things unfinished.
나는 일을 미완성 상태로 두지 않습니다.
The word unfinished is not in my dictionary.
끝나지 않았다는 말 내 사전에는 없어.
I'll make sure to add the secret sauce.
비법소스도 꼭 추가할게요.
And thanks to your help,
그리고 여러분의 도움 덕분에,
it's already so good even without the secret sauce.
벌써 너무 좋아 비법 소스가 없어도.
Ms. Park,
박 선생님,
this isn't the last time you're helping us with kimchi.
이번이 마지막이 아니야 당신은 김치로 우리를 돕고 있어요.
You'll continue to help us next year and the year after.
계속해서 우리를 도와주실 거예요 내년에도, 내후에도.
You will, right?
그럴 거예요, 그렇죠?
Next year and the year after?
내년과 내후년?
I look forward to seeing you, Ms. Park.
박 선생님, 뵙기를 기대합니다.
If you keep moving your hand,
계속해서 손을 움직이면
it won't heal fast.
빨리 낫지 않을 거예요.
Don't make me worry.
걱정하게 만들지 마세요.
(LAUGHS) Mr. Kwon.
(웃음) 권 선생님.
How did you get such a nice daughter-in-law?
어떻게 얻었나요? 이렇게 좋은 며느리야?
Like father-in-law, like daughter-in-law.
시아버지처럼, 며느리처럼.
(BOTH LAUGH)
(둘 다 웃음)
You should go rest.
넌 가서 쉬어야 해.
-Okay. -Bye.
-좋아요. -안녕.
YURA: Mirim, where are you? Did you meet Jihoon?
유라: 미림아, 어디야? 지훈이랑 만났어?
(EXHALING DEEPLY)
(깊이 숨을 내쉬며)
(INHALING DEEPLY)
(깊이 흡입)
Oh.
아.
(EXHALES)
(숨을 내쉬다)
Relax and breathe.
긴장을 풀고 숨을 쉬십시오.
MIRIM, WHERE ARE YOU? DID YOU MEET JIHOON?
미림 씨, 어디 있어요? 지훈을 만났나요?
Oh. It's Yura.
오. 유라입니다.
(EXHALES)
(숨을 내쉬다)
MIRIM: Like you said,
미림: 말씀하신 대로요.
I'm doing yoga with Jihoon for Bboongbboong.
나 지훈이랑 요가하고 있어 붕붕을 위해.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
-Jihoon. -Yes?
-지훈. -예?
I guess everyone loves me.
모두가 나를 사랑하는 것 같아요.
(CHUCKLES)
(웃음)
What makes you say that?
왜 그런 말을 하게 됐나요?
When Yura heard my stomach feels tight,
유라가 내 배가 조이는 소리를 듣고
she paid for yoga right away.
그녀는 바로 요가 비용을 지불했습니다.
Honey,
여보,
that's not because she loves you, but because she loves me.
그건 그 사람이 널 사랑해서가 아니야. 하지만 그녀는 나를 사랑하기 때문에.
I'm the one
나는 그 사람이다
that everyone loves.
모두가 좋아하는 것.
Speaking of Yura,
유라에 대해 말하자면,
didn't she look weird today?
오늘 그 사람 좀 이상해 보이지 않았어?
She was very distracted.
그녀는 매우 산만했습니다.
JIHOON: Right.
지훈: 그렇죠.
-Jihoon, breathe. -Okay.
- 지훈아, 숨 쉬어라. -좋아요.
KID: See you tomorrow.
아이: 내일 봐요.
Minseo!
민서!
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Good girl. (CHUCKLES)
좋은 여자. (웃음)
Mom.
엄마.
I thought about what to do with Uncle Taegu today.
나는 무엇을 해야할지 생각했다 오늘은 대구삼촌과 함께.
I have 39 ideas.
나에게는 39개의 아이디어가 있다.
Do you want to see?
보고 싶나요?
Minseo. (HESITATING)
민서. (머뭇거림)
Don't stay too close to him.
그 사람에게 너무 가까이 있지 마십시오.
Why? Does he hate me?
왜? 그 사람이 나를 싫어하나요?
No, it's nothing like that.
아니요, 그런 것이 아닙니다.
He's not as cheerful as we are.
그 사람은 우리만큼 유쾌하지 않아요.
He might feel a little uncomfortable.
그 사람은 좀 불편할 수도 있겠네요.
Okay?
좋아요?
If that's what he's like, okay.
그 사람이 그런 사람이라면 괜찮습니다.
Smart girl.
똑똑한 소녀.
There.
거기.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Mom.
엄마.
Do you hate Uncle Taegu?
대구삼촌이 싫어?
No.
아니요.
Get inside.
안으로 들어가세요.
(GATE OPENS)
(게이트가 열림)
-(SIGHS) -(GATE CLOSES)
-(한숨) -(게이트가 닫힙니다)
-(CELL PHONE BEEPS) -(LINE RINGING)
-(휴대폰 신호음) -(라인 벨 울림)
Dohoon.
도훈.
Well...
음...
Can you pick Minseo up after work?
퇴근 후에 민서를 데리러 올 수 있나요?
She's at Father's.
그녀는 아버지 집에 있어요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
We need to finish our talk.
우리 얘기를 끝내야 해요.
Come to the café.
카페로 오세요.
-(SNIFFS) -(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
-(훌쩍훌쩍) -(휴대폰이 진동함)
WE NEED TO FINISH OUR TALK COME TO THE CAFÉ
우리 얘기를 끝내야 해 카페로 오세요
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(부드럽게 낄낄거린다)
-(CELL PHONE BEEPS) -(LINE RINGING)
-(휴대폰 신호음) -(라인 벨 울림)
Tonight,
오늘 밤,
finish Hwacha.
화차를 마쳐라.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(다가오는 발자국)
CHIEF OH: Is this the life you wanted?
오 수석: 이것이 당신이 원했던 삶인가요?
Holding yourself back from seeing her
그녀를 만나지 않으려고 스스로를 참는다
until you can't hold it back anymore.
더 이상 참을 수 없을 때까지.
Don't you want to live together
같이 살고 싶지 않니?
with your daughter and granddaughter?
딸, 손녀와 함께?
I can grant you that wish.
나는 당신에게 그 소원을 들어줄 수 있습니다.
Where's my daughter? Tell me.
내 딸은 어디 있지? 말해 주세요.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
She's in a safe place.
그녀는 안전한 곳에 있어요.
Why are you doing this?
왜 이러는 걸까요?
I told you,
내가 말했잖아,
I can't undo what's already done.
이미 이루어진 일은 되돌릴 수 없습니다.
I told you as well.
나는 당신에게도 말했다.
When I put Warrior on trial,
내가 Warrior를 재판에 회부했을 때,
I would need you.
나는 당신이 필요합니다.
You're the last witness to verify that history.
당신이 마지막 증인이에요 그 역사를 확인하기 위해.
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
I promise I'll protect your daughter and granddaughter.
내가 지켜줄게 약속해 당신의 딸과 손녀.
Join me.
나와 함께하세요.
This is your last chance to repent.
이번이 회개할 수 있는 마지막 기회입니다.
Join hands with me.
나와 손을 잡으세요.
What if I refuse?
거절하면 어떻게 되나요?
Did it sound like a suggestion?
제안처럼 들렸나요?
I'm not suggesting, I'm threatening.
제안하는 게 아니고 협박하는 거예요.
You think you can give up on your family?
포기해도 된다고 생각하는가? 당신의 가족에?
(SCOFFS)
(비웃음)
(EXHALES)
(숨을 내쉬다)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
When I looked into Koo Inbo, he had no connection with the Union.
구인보를 들여다보니, 그는 연합과 아무런 관련이 없습니다.
His past activities in Japan were clear.
그의 과거 일본에서의 활동은 분명했다.
The problem is Ma Yeonrim.
문제는 마연림이다.
Why? Does she have something to do with the Union?
왜? 그녀는 할 일이 있나요? 연합이랑?
Hmm. No,
흠. 아니요,
but it's strange that she has nothing.
그런데 그녀에게 아무것도 없다는 것이 이상합니다.
She changed her name three times,
그녀는 이름을 세 번이나 바꾸었고,
but I couldn't find anything about her past.
하지만 난 아무것도 찾을 수 없었어 그녀의 과거에 대해.
Normally, when you trace it back,
일반적으로 추적해 보면
you find something.
당신은 뭔가를 발견합니다.
But nothing.
하지만 아무것도.
There's none.
아무것도 없습니다.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(손가락을 찰칵)
Wiped her history clean.
그녀의 역사를 깨끗하게 지웠습니다.
If she's that clean, the government must've been involved.
그 사람이 그렇게 깨끗하다면, 정부가 개입했을 겁니다.
What's her address?
그 사람 주소가 뭐예요?
She has nothing under her name.
그녀의 이름에는 아무것도 없습니다.
She was running a store under someone else's name.
그녀는 가게를 운영하고 있었어요 다른 사람 이름으로.
She also pays for electricity regularly.
그녀는 또한 정기적으로 전기 요금을 지불합니다.
Okay, thanks.
알았어, 고마워.
Text me the address.
주소를 문자로 보내주세요.
Are you going now?
지금 가시나요?
Who on Earth is Ma Yeonrim?
마연림은 도대체 누구인가?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(초인종 벨소리)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(문이 삐걱거리는 소리)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
Do you have any design in mind?
염두에 두고 있는 디자인이 있나요?
Ms. Ma Yeonrim.
마연림 선생님.
What's your relationship with Oh Chunryun?
당신의 관계는 무엇입니까 오춘련이랑?
You're not even surprised.
당신은 놀라지도 않습니다.
(SIGHS SOFTLY)
(부드럽게 한숨을 쉬다)
While you were checking on me,
당신이 나를 확인하는 동안,
I checked you too.
나도 당신을 확인했습니다.
You checked the exit as you entered
입장과 동시에 출구를 확인했습니다.
and have your back to it, so I can't escape.
그리고 그것에 등을 돌리십시오. 그래서 나는 탈출할 수 없다.
Securing sharp objects
날카로운 물건을 안전하게 보호
within your reach.
당신의 손이 닿는 곳에.
You can't hide your habits.
습관을 숨길 수는 없습니다.
Then you probably noticed
그럼 아마 눈치챘겠지
I won't be a threat.
나는 위협이 되지 않을 것이다.
How do you know
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Oh Chunryun?
아 춘륜?
You tell me first.
당신이 먼저 말해 보세요.
I'm her friend.
나는 그녀의 친구입니다.
Close enough to advise her
그녀에게 조언할 만큼 가까워요
to dig her eyes out if she's looking in the wrong direction.
그녀가 보고 있다면 눈을 파내려고 잘못된 방향으로.
She and I were friends too.
그녀와 나도 친구였습니다.
Unfortunately,
불행하게도,
that's all I can tell you.
그것이 내가 당신에게 말할 수 있는 전부입니다.
You'd want to hear it from her.
당신은 그녀에게서 그것을 듣고 싶을 것입니다.
For both her sake and yours.
그녀와 당신을 위해.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
DOHOON: Have you identified the suspect? The sniper who shot Wolfe.
도훈: 용의자를 특정했나요? 울프를 쏜 저격수.
You know the rule.
당신은 규칙을 알고 있습니다.
Stay out of it.
그것을 멀리하십시오.
You're excluding me on purpose.
당신은 일부러 나를 제외하고 있습니다.
How can I not worry about it?
어떻게 걱정하지 않을 수 있습니까?
Chief Oh.
오 과장.
The tattoos on Carly Young and Wolfe,
Carly Young과 Wolfe의 문신,
what are they?
그들은 무엇입니까?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
19, WOOSUNG-GIL, JIJUNG-MYEON, WONJU, GANGWON
지중면 우성길 19, 강원도 원주
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
Wonju?
원주?
TO OH CHUNRYUN
오천륜에게
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
-(CELL PHONE BEEPS) -(LINE RINGING)
-(휴대폰 신호음) -(라인 벨 울림)
19, Woosung-gil, Jijung-myeon, Wonju, Gangwon.
경기도 지정면 우성길 19 강원도 원주.
It's Hwacha's address.
화차님의 주소입니다.
Move with Team A.
A팀과 함께 이동하세요.
I'll set off now.
이제 출발하겠습니다.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(감동적인 음악이 계속됩니다)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(기계 신호음)
(GRUNTING)
(끙끙거림)
One MGD killer died on the spot.
MGD 킬러 한 명이 그 자리에서 사망했습니다.
The other was captured alive.
다른 한 명은 살아서 붙잡혔습니다.
Well done. What about Hwacha?
잘하셨어요. 화차는 어때요?
He was already dead when we arrived.
우리가 도착했을 때 그는 이미 죽어 있었습니다.
The nurse said
간호사가 말했다.
he was in a coma since last week due to pneumonia complications.
그 사람 지난주부터 혼수상태였어 폐렴 합병증으로 인해.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(휴대전화 진동)
Hello?
안녕하세요?
MAN: I received the report.
MAN: 보고서를 받았어요.
Now that Hwacha's gone,
이제 화차는 없어졌으니
we're off to a good start.
우리는 좋은 출발을 하고 있어요.
How long to clean it up?
언제까지 청소해야 하나요?
We're almost done.
이제 거의 끝났습니다.
We'll be leaving soon.
우리는 곧 떠날 거예요.
When you return, you can interrogate him the old way
돌아올 때, 그 사람을 옛날 방식으로 심문하면 돼
until he confesses everything.
그가 모든 것을 고백할 때까지.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(침울한 음악 재생)
-(CELL PHONE BEEPS) -(LINE RINGING)
-(휴대폰 신호음) -(라인 벨 울림)
I got a gift.
선물을 받았습니다.
I need to know who sent it.
누가 보냈는지 알아야 해요.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
(LOCK BEEPS)
(잠금 신호음)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(깊은 한숨)
-Bottoms up. -(CHEERING)
-바닥을 위로. -(응원)
Bottoms up.
상향식.
Nice.
멋진.
It's been so long
너무 오랜만이야
since we drank together.
같이 마셨으니까.
You cried last time.
너 지난번에 울었잖아.
It was Cherry's farewell party.
체리의 송별회였습니다.
You begged her not to leave. (LAUGHING)
당신은 그녀에게 떠나지 말라고 간청했습니다. (웃음)
CHERRY: For real?
체리: 진짜요?
You're complete strangers without me.
나 없이는 당신은 완전히 낯선 사람입니다.
We're total strangers.
우리는 완전히 낯선 사람입니다.
Hang on.
잠깐만요.
Then in this dreary company,
그렇다면 이 음울한 회사에서
I must have been like an oasis?
나는 분명 오아시스 같았을 텐데?
Really? Is that what I was?
정말? 내가 그랬던 걸까?
Uh...
어...
She hates me so much.
그 사람은 나를 너무 싫어해요.
Women should stick together.
여자들은 뭉쳐야 합니다.
Chunryun. Just because I'm prettier than you
춘륜. 단지 내가 너보다 예뻐서
you think it's okay to ostracize me
넌 나를 배척해도 괜찮다고 생각하는구나
-Right? -No.
- 그렇죠? -아니요.
-Never. -CHERRY: Then you should drink.
-절대. -체리: 그럼 마셔야지.
Then you should drink.
그럼 마셔야지.
What's the matter with you?
당신에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
-She's ostracizing you. -(ALL LAUGH)
-그녀는 당신을 배척하고 있어요. -(모두 웃음)
I mean, it's true that I hate you.
내가 당신을 싫어하는 건 사실이에요.
But everyone in the company hates you except for him.
그런데 회사 사람들이 다 당신을 싫어해요. 그를 제외하고.
(GROANS)
(신음소리)
Besides,
게다가,
you're not the only one.
당신은 유일한 사람이 아닙니다.
I hate all of you.
나는 너희 모두를 싫어한다.
(ALL GROAN)
(모두 신음)
I know you don't mean that.
나는 당신이 그런 뜻이 아니라는 것을 압니다.
Don't be shy.
부끄러워하지 마세요.
I heard something about you.
당신에 대해 뭔가 들었어요.
What?
무엇?
When you were new, you refused to eat for three weeks because of Dohoon.
당신이 신입이었을 때, 당신은 식사를 거부했습니다 도훈 때문에 3주간.
-Because of me? -CHERRY: Yes.
-나 때문에요? -체리: 네.
She thought you died in the field. (GASPS)
그녀는 당신이 죽은 줄 알았는데 현장에서. (가스프)
"My friend Dohoon died." (SOBBING MOCKINGLY)
"내 친구 도훈이가 죽었어." (조롱하게 흐느끼며)
(LAUGHING) And she cried.
(웃음) 그리고 그녀는 울었습니다.
You.
너.
When she thought you were dead,
그녀가 당신이 죽었다고 생각했을 때,
she cried her eyes out
그녀는 눈이 멀도록 울었다
and got a tattoo.
그리고 문신을 했어요.
Even though it hurt.
비록 아팠지만.
"In loving memory of Lim Jaeyeol".
"임재열을 추억하며".
(IN ENGLISH) LJY".
(영어로) LJY".
(IN KOREAN) Seriously, Oh Chunryun.
(IN KOREAN) 진심으로요, 오춘련님.
I covered it up with Buddha a long time ago.
부처로 덮어버렸네 오래 전.
Stop talking about the old days. You're so out of style.
옛날 얘기는 그만하세요. 당신은 너무 스타일이 뒤떨어져 있어요.
Speaking of which,
말하자면,
-should I get a tattoo? -What?
-문신을 해야 하나? - 뭐?
I've had something in mind.
생각해 둔 게 있어요.
Do you have a pen? Give me a pen.
펜 있어요? 펜을 주세요.
Okay.
알았어.
Hold on. Keep drinking.
잠깐만요. 계속 마셔요.
One second.
1초.
CHERRY: This is salty.
체리: 이건 짭짤해요.
DOHOON: Like this.
도훈: 이렇게요.
CHERRY: This is perfect for beer.
체리: 맥주에 딱이네요.
It's good, right?
좋은 것 맞죠?
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
What do you say?
당신은 무엇을 말합니까?
Good? Where should I do it?
좋은? 어디서 해야 하나요?
Here?
여기?
Oh Chunryun.
아 춘륜.
Where should I do it?
어디서 해야 하나요?
Tell me, where?
말해봐, 어디야?
(GLASS THUDS)
(유리 쿵)
Follow me.
나를 따르라.
Why?
왜?
But it's cold.
하지만 춥습니다.
I should put my jacket on.
재킷을 입어야겠어요.
Hey. Don't.
여기요. 하지 않다.
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
Hey.
여기요.
Stay out.
밖으로 나가세요.
(EXHALES)
(숨을 내쉬다)
What a moron.
정말 바보입니다.
She's got served.
그녀는 봉사를 받았습니다.
What's the matter with him?
그에게 무슨 문제가 있는 걸까요?
This is scary.
이건 무섭다.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(혀를 클릭함)
So... (CLEARS THROAT)
그럼... (목을 가다듬는다)
Going home tonight?
오늘 밤 집에 갈까?
Of course I'm going home.
물론 저는 집에 갈 거예요.
My home?
내 집?
CHERRY: Huh?
체리: 응?
(DOHOON EXHALES)
(도훈이 한숨을 쉰다)
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
All right.
괜찮은.
Let's stop playing hide and seek.
숨바꼭질 놀이는 그만하자.
This isn't like me.
이건 나와 같지 않습니다.
I can't do this anymore.
나는 더 이상 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
You were digging up dirt on me.
당신은 나에게 흙을 파고 있었어요.
What?
무엇?
It wasn't what you were looking for?
당신이 찾고 있던 것이 아니었나요?
(CHUCKLES) Do you know who I met before I came here?
(웃음) 내가 누구를 만났는지 아세요? 내가 여기 오기 전에?
Ma Yeonrim.
마연림.
Or should I say Butterfly?
아니면 나비라고 해야 할까요?
So? What did Ma Yeonrim say?
그래서? 마연림이 뭐라고 했어요?
No.
아니요.
That's a wrong question.
그건 잘못된 질문이에요.
Did you tell her that I tried to kill Ma Yeonrim?
그녀에게 말했나요? 내가 마연림을 죽이려고 했다고?
(CHUCKLING)
(낄낄거림)
I was going to,
내가 가려던 건,
but that old lady looked somewhat fishy.
그런데 그 노부인은 좀 수상해 보였습니다.
You know I'm good at smelling.
나 냄새 잘 맡는 거 알잖아.
Stop racking your brain.
두뇌를 괴롭히지 마세요.
Don't try to read my mind.
내 마음을 읽으려고 하지 마세요.
I already showed you my mind.
나는 이미 당신에게 내 마음을 보여주었습니다.
Oh Chunryun.
아 춘륜.
I told you.
내가 말했잖아.
I owe you my life.
나는 당신에게 내 생명을 빚지고 있습니다.
You can talk to me. Hmm?
당신은 나에게 얘기할 수 있습니다. 흠?
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(침울한 음악 재생)
(SCOFFS SOFTLY)
(부드럽게 비웃는다)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(문을 두드리는 소리)
Don't fight.
싸우지 마세요.
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
(SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES)
(침울한 음악이 계속됩니다)
(YAWNING) Hmm...
(하품) 흠...
Chunryun.
춘륜.
Do you like Cherry that much?
체리를 그렇게 좋아해요?
Were you worried about Cherry going home by herself?
체리가 집에 갈까 걱정됐나요 혼자서?
Hey.
여기요.
You're leaking him info, aren't you?
당신은 그 사람의 정보를 유출하고 있는 거죠, 그렇죠?
No.
아니요.
I don't want to interfere between the two of you,
방해하고 싶지 않아요 너희 둘 사이에,
but you better not mix it up.
하지만 섞지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Don't mix up information on your own.
혼자서 정보를 혼동하지 마십시오.
Okay.
좋아요.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(휴대전화 진동)
BUTTERFLY
나비
(VIBRATING STOPS)
(진동 정지)
(SIGHS)
(한숨)
Do you want to come to my house?
우리 집에 올래?
Do you think I'm crazy?
내가 미친 것 같아?
My pretty daughter and wife are waiting for me at home.
나의 예쁜 딸과 아내는 집에서 나를 기다리고 있어요.
(SIGHS) Right?
(한숨) 그렇죠?
Then
그 다음에
can you take me to your house?
나를 당신 집에 데려다 줄 수 있나요?
(SIGHS) I really
(한숨) 난 정말
don't want to go home alone tonight.
오늘 밤은 혼자 집에 가고 싶지 않아요.
I'm serious.
나는 진지하다.
Hey.
여기요.
You're so pathetic.
당신은 정말 한심해요.
Take me home.
집에 데려다주세요.
Buddy.
친구.
I'm saying no seriously.
나는 진지하게 아니라고 말하고있다.
Go home, say the Lord's Prayer
집에 가서 주기도문을 드려라
and sleep tight, okay?
그리고 푹 자, 알았지?
Go to bed, you prick.
자러가라, 이 새끼야.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
(휴대폰이 진동함)
You're so mean.
당신은 정말 못됐어요.
Your wife?
당신의 아내?
BUTTERFLY: Can you come to the tattoo shop now?
나비: 올 수 있나요? 지금 문신 가게로 가?
Shall we ask her at least?
최소한 그녀에게 물어볼까요?
I haven't seen Minseo for a long time.
민서를 오랫동안 보지 못했어요.
Then...
그럼...
-Right. -Taxi.
- 그렇죠. -택시.
JAEYEOL: Right.
재열: 그렇죠.
Does Minseo like pork hocks,
민서는 족발을 좋아하나요,
or fried chicken?
아니면 후라이드 치킨?
Huh?
뭐?
I'll...
난...
What am I supposed to do?
나는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(심호흡)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(부드럽게 신음)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(가쁜 숨을 들이쉰다)
-(CELL PHONE BEEPS) -(LINE RINGING)
-(휴대폰 신호음) -(라인 벨 울림)
Honey, are you coming home?
여보, 집에 가나요?
-Where's Minseo? -DOHOON: Is your cousin home yet?
-민서는 어디 있어요? -도훈: 사촌은 아직 집에 있나요?
I asked him to pick Minseo up.
나는 그에게 민서를 데리러 오라고 했다.
When was that?
그게 언제였나요?
Why? Is everything all right?
왜? 모든 것이 괜찮습니까?
No, I got to go.
아니, 가야 해.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(라인 연결 끊김)
(LOCK KEYPAD BEEPING)
(잠금 키패드 소리)
-(LOCK CHIMES) -(DOOR UNLOCKS)
-(잠금 차임) -(문 잠금 해제)
(LOCK CHIMES)
(잠금 차임)
-Uncle, it was fun today. -Hmm.
-삼촌, 오늘 즐거웠어요. -흠.
-Mom. -(YURA CHUCKLES)
-엄마. -(유라 낄낄거림)
Uncle Taegu took me to the playground
대구삼촌이 날 놀이터에 데려갔어
and bought me snacks.
그리고 간식도 사줬어요.
Did he?
그랬나요?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(소프트 음악 재생)
UNCLE Taegu
삼촌 대구
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(발소리가 쿵쿵)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(침울한 음악 재생)
Uncle Taegu.
대구아저씨.
(YURA GRUNTS)
(유라 그런츠)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(감동적인 음악 재생)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(음악 재생)
FAMILY: THE UNBREAKABLE BOND
가족: 깨지지 않는 유대
YURA: You won't live to see another day if you mess with my family.
유라: 넌 살아서 하루를 더 볼 수 없을 거야 내 가족을 건드린다면.
MINSEO: Start!
민서: 시작해요!
(YELLING)
(고함)
-I think I'll win. -(LAUGHS)
-내가 이길 것 같아요. -(웃음)
One more time.
한 번 더.
CHIEF OH: Get this one first.
OH 최고: 이것을 먼저 얻으세요.
DOHOON: It's Taegu.
도훈: 대구예요.
TAEGU: Now you remember who I am.
대구: 이제 내가 누군지 기억나시죠?
Right, Wind?
그렇지, 바람?
YURA: This is the final chance.
유라: 이것이 마지막 기회입니다.
Whatever the mission,
임무가 무엇이든,
I could rely on her.
나는 그녀에게 의지할 수 있었다.
-TAEGU: Prove your skills. -(GUNSHOT)
- 대구: 실력을 증명해 보세요. -(총소리)
-(PEOPLE CLAMORING) -You have two days.
-(사람들이 소리친다) - 이틀 남았습니다.